GM Adam Peters if you follow mock drafts
but even over the last week there were
about 18 different people that were
linked to Washington. So this was an
interesting draft and you ended up with
Sunny Styles. At what point in the
process did you kind of peg him as
somebody that you'd like to be a
commander?
>> Yeah, really throughout the whole
process he was always a guy that was on
our radar. Uh he's he's a special kid.
He's been on the radar for a long time.
He was he was a big-time recruit. He was
a safety that that uh moved a linebacker
a couple years ago, but you had always
seen him. You always knew who he was.
Even three, four years ago, the the area
scouts that are in there, they know who
Sunonny Styles, you know, and they said,
"That's Sunny Styles." And then you kind
of watch him, he changed some numbers
over the years, but um you know, he
always stood out as an athlete. And then
him becoming a linebacker the last
couple of years, it was uh it was really
cool to see the evolution. And then um
there's just so much love for him in our
building throughout the process, you
know, starting with our first set of
meetings uh with the college scouts and
then with the coaches and then again as
as we got into the draft meetings and
then R&D is they love him and all his
metrics and and everything and then
obviously the combine to the combine and
so you know the momentum grew and grew
and grew and uh felt really great about
it throughout the whole process until
this last week. really um comfortable,
you know, more than comfortable sitting
there and taking him, but it was just a
matter of was he going to be there?
>> Yeah.
>> Right.
>> So, were you I mean, it sounds like cuz
like Bram and I had a bet. He bet me a
dollar that Sunny I said Sunny Sway he's
going to be there. Bram's like he's
going to be there. Were you surprised
that he was there at seven for the pick
>> a little bit? Yeah. I I thought um you
know you know if you did the probability
and and all that it it was not it was
much more improbable than probable. So,
and there was there's a lot of teams
that were in front of us that I thought
would would want them. And um so it's
just the way the board fell. And then
when when Kansas City traded up um you
know, I I kind of figured they weren't
trading up for for a linebacker. So um
you know, I felt felt great there.
>> You start smiling a little bit more.
>> So So I played with Lorenzo's dad. I
mean, I'm sorry, with Sunny's dad,
Lorenzo Styles back in with the Rams. 99
Rams. We were we were teammates on the
Super Bowl team. Um, and I text with
Lorenzo over the last few uh couple
years. And then recently after Sunny had
that showing at the combine, I
congratulated him on his son's showings
and everything. And I was like, man,
they crushed it. He's like, "Yeah, man.
I would love, this was March 18th, he
said, "Man, I would love for him to
actually end up in Washington."
And when he said that, I was like,
"Yeah, I would love to be talking
about." So, did you get to get the sense
that he really wanted to be a commander
during the process?
>> Yeah, especially in the 30 visit, you
could tell he expressed that and he
expressed that to a lot of our coaches,
too. And the feeling was mutual, you
know. So, but um yeah, just uh he is he
is what it means to be a commander. You
know, he got our commander tag and and
you know, through and through like it
wasn't even a question. And so, um that
part of it was easy. And uh that's cool
that that that he's this day.
>> I'll show you a text afterwards.
>> He'll be here tomorrow. I'll be coming
tomorrow. Yeah. So come come hang. Yeah.
>> So another thing you mentioned about
Sunny being a a safety at one point.
Played two years a safety and then just
two seasons as a linebacker. You saw his
tape a year ago. Then this year I mean
just the
>> the ascend ascension of him at the
position. Do you all still feel like I
feel like he's just scratching the
surface
>> of his potential as a linebacker. Do you
all kind of see his ceiling as through
the roof?
>> Yeah. I mean, he took the words right
out of my mouth like he's got getting
better and better. Even throughout this
year, I I just said this to our our
local press, but just throughout the
year, he got better and better, and he's
playing his best ball at the end of the
year toward those late games and then
the championship game and then in the
playoffs. and so better at all those
traits that you know that you you're
talking about like whether it's playing
in the box, whether it's blitzing, whe
all the little nuances of the game and
yeah, he's just scratching the surface.
So, he's already a great player. I don't
want to certainly take the way that he's
a, you know, he's already great, but I
think he's got another level.
>> I want to ask you about evaluation when
you have
>> he had talented teammates with him. Two
of them, one went right before him and
one went right after him. All of them
could have been top 10 picks. When you
evaluate a player that has that kind of
talent around them, how do you take into
totality that group and the individual
play that you watch from that one
particular player?
>> Yeah. One, it's really fun to watch.
It's it's great. Like I watched every
play of their defense and so it not not
cuz I'm trying to be Mr. Hardo Scout,
but like
>> just fun. Like it was fun. And they're
they have an outstanding coach. Matt
Patricia is a great coach. you know,
these guys have been coached really,
really well. They're they're on the
details. They understand their role in
the defense. They communicate really
well. So, you see that all coming
together and everybody owning their
role. And so, um, so it's it was just
fun to watch. And so, I would lock in on
say I'm watching their I'm watching
Arll, but you you're locking in on him,
but then you're kind of watching
everybody else. And then I do one at a
time. So, you watch it over and over.
You watch a corner and they got a lot of
guys on that defense. They're really
good. And um obviously three, you know,
guys who were almost top 10 picks and so
um but you see, you know, as you're
watching the other guys, you see Sunny
flashing all the time and just how how
big and long and fast he is. And so he's
always jumping out at the tape, but
certainly hats off to Matt Patricia and
that defense and and it's fun. It's it's
uh it's easy. It's an easy watch. Some
of these aren't aren't that easy. That's
an easy watch.
>> You talked about the commander tag. Can
you talk about like what goes into that
formula of determining a commander a
little bit? Obviously, like when you cut
when you cut the film off, he's a
physical freak, but I think it's cool
that you guys identify the person as
well, like what goes into that
evaluation, you know, to get him here.
>> Yeah. And that that's really our scouts.
our scouts are digging in and all the
work they put in really like I said I
mean these guys have been watching him
for a couple years and
>> and then they go in and they get all the
information on what type of person he
is, the leader that he is, the
communicator that he is, this
quarterback of that defense and getting
the guys lined up up front and so his
football intelligence, his football
character, all those different things
that go into it and you know you you put
a score on it, you know, you really and
um and So he he he passed everything
with flying colors, you know, in terms
of all those things and and um you know,
he's he's a team captain type. He he's
all those things and and uh just an
awesome guy off the field, too. When you
um this is your third draft here as a
general manager in Washington. First two
years you're drafting for different type
of offensive scheme, different type of
defensive scheme. Now you got Donte
Jones defense, you got David Blas
offense. How was it going through that
process with these guys kind trying to
figure out, okay, what are they looking
for in terms of what's the best type of
uh player to fit their their um schemes
and systems offensively and defensively?
>> Yeah, it was really fun and those guys
when they came in um they presented to
all of us really the whole you know
organization football side in terms of
what we're looking for at each position,
what how we're going to play offense,
how we're going to play defense. And so
those guys, you know, in that auditorium
over there, they stood up and presented
with clips and and went through position
by position. So they painted a great
picture for us. And then uh you know,
both those guys have been excellent
communicators and teachers and and so
doors open go by and kind of just chop
it up and say, "All right, um what do
you think about this? What do you think
about?" And so um not only do they
present, but they're they're open at
answering questions and and giving us
examples. So that process has been
really good. and they've been they were
in the free agency meetings, they were
in the draft meetings. Um so hearing
them and their you know one their
involvement, their buyin u in terms of
our processes have been awesome and then
their input in in teaching us like how
how these guys fit, how Sunny will fit
in the defense and and different guys
like that. It's it's really been fun.
Those guys are awesome. When you met
with the media a week ago, you talked
about all the signings that had occurred
in free agency that didn't box you in to
having to make a choice at a position.
As this week progressed, were you
leaning offense or defense or were you
just going to wait and see how the board
played out?
>> Yeah, just wait and see how the board
played out. Yeah, it was uh I think
especially when you're when you're that
high, you just get just get a great
player.
>> You know, you figure out the rest, you
know, and uh I think we we did that.
Yeah.
>> Um so what's the next couple of days?
cuz I know there's a long wait. Yeah. In
between picks, but what are you looking
for over the next couple of days?
>> Um yeah, we we have the pick 71 um which
is our only pick tomorrow and I think
it'd be kind of tough to add another one
at this point if we didn't do it with
that pick. So um it's just waiting and
and praying that our guys don't don't
come off the board. But no, honestly,
we'll get together and and just really
go through the different iterations of
all right, if not this, then this, and
if these guys, these two guys are on the
board, who we're picking, and hopefully
there's a few guys to choose from where
you can either just pick the best one or
you can even trade down. So, just
talking through those things beforehand.
Um, kind of like we did with this pick,
you know, we we we did all all kinds of
exercises about trades and who could be
there, who who not could be there, and
then nobody called for the trade. So,
all that work, we could have done
something else, but
but uh no, you have to you have to be
ready for everything. And so, we'll do
the same thing with that. Yeah.
>> Uh you should have seen us after you
guys made the pick. We were excited,
too. We were very excited about the pick
of Sunny Styles. Congratulations on the
selection and good luck with the rest of
the draft. Thanks so much.
>> Yeah. Thanks, B. Thanks, guys.
>> Cool. That awesome.